and what, what, are you so bothered by questions about
а что что вас так напрягают вопросы о
your independence, why are you afraid of
вашей независимости почему вы боитесь
these questions, what questions, well, are you
этих вопросов
afraid to remember and
Татарстана боитесь вспоминать и
talk about the independence of Tatarstan? I just, I just have
разговаривать я я просто я просто об
n’t even thought about it now, let’s
этом даже не думал сейчас давайте
think, let’s think, look, I’m
подумаем давайте подумаем вот смотрите я
asking such a theoretical question, if
такой теоретический вопрос задаю если
Tatarstan will be an independent state,
Татарстан будет независимым государством
no, I don’t even want to think about it,
нет я я даже думать не хочу
hello,
здравствуйте
hello, I’m from the city of Khmelnitsky, where are you
здравствуйте я из города Хмельницкий вы
from,
откуда
Kazan, Tatarstan, are
казань Татарстан
you a Tatar? Yes, probably, I
вы татарин
mean, probably, you’re not sure, well,
в смысле наверно вы не уверены
mom said so, yes, dad said so, yes, probably, I understood that no, no, there’s no point in this
ну мама сказала так да папа сказал так
grinning, no, well, like, you’re not sure,
хмылках не ну что типа вы не уверены что
then you don’t know who
вы тогда не знаете кто
you are, but you know the Tatar language, yes, I know how to say bread in Tatar and pi, and freedom, how to say svoboda in Tatar, and zatlok is correct, and how to say free Tatarstan in Tatar, what is this all about, the collapse of the Russian Federation? No, that’s what you’re leading to, yes, I’m leading to
нет ты же это к чему ты ведёшь да веду к
that. I know what you’re leading to,
тому я Я знаю к чему ты это ведёшь к
what am I leading to?  you all have
чему я это веду у вас у вас же у всех
all this you are all leading to the same thing what the
это всё вы же все же к одному ведёте то
hell what are we leading Tatarstan to in
что блин да к чему мы ведём татарстан в
1991 damn you could have
девяносто первом году блин вы же могли
separated damn so in
отсоединиться блин так в девяносто
1992 you accepted the referendum
втором году вы же приняли референдум
held yes about independence yes yes well of
проводили да о независимости да да ну
course of course well you are leading to all this
конечно конечно ну вы же к этому всему
I am not just asking
ведётесь не я просто спрашиваю
but just asking what what are you so
а просто спрашиваю а что что вас так
bothered by questions about your independence
напрягают вопросы о вашей независимости
why are you afraid of these questions
почему вы боитесь этих вопросов
what questions well about the independence of
каких вопросах ну о независимости
Tatarstan you are afraid to remember and
Татарстана боитесь вспоминать и
talk about I just I just have
разговаривать я я просто я просто об
n't even thought about it now let's
этом даже не думал сейчас давайте
think let's think look I am
подумаем давайте подумаем вот смотрите я
asking such a theoretical question if
такой теоретический вопрос задаю если
Tatarstan will be an independent state
Татарстан будет независимым государством
No I am Yes I don't even want to think you
Нет я я Да я я даже думать не хочу
understand I want to find I No you are
понимаешь я хочу нахо я Нет вы же вы же
also striving for the European Union for some reason I am
тоже стремитесь в Евросоюз почему-то я
striving from Ukraine don't wait
из Украины стремлюсь не подождите
Ukraine is striving somewhere yes yes to the
украина стремится куда-то ж да да в
European Union The European Union or somewhere else for
Евросоюз Евросоюз или ещё куда-то
some reason it doesn't want to be alone
почему-то она же не хочет одна
no well look we are independent  the
находиться не ну смотрите мы независимое
state and we want to be in the European Union
государство и мы хотим быть в Евросоюзе
this is the Union of Independent States so
это Союз независимых государств так
why for example Tatarstan yes if
почему например Татарстан да вот если бы
it were also but no you get it no so that's how it is
он тоже был а нет у вас получается нет
say wait it doesn't
так вот вот так говори подожди
work why are you
получается не получается почему ты
afraid to discuss whether Tatarstan can be
боишься обсудить может ли Татарстан быть
independent that is whether it will be able to survive
независимым то есть сможет ли он выжить
economically and so on there is
экономически и так далее компетенции
no such competence you understand let's discuss this
такой нет понимаешь вот это обсуждать
at the level of ordinary citizens I don't have
давай на уровне простых граждан у меня
such an education let's
образования вот такого нету это всё
discuss all this you understand well imagine that
обсуждать понимаешь ну вот представь что
tomorrow Putin says: "We are excluding
завтра Путин скажет: "Мы исключаем
Tatarstan from the Russian Federation we don't
Татарстан из Российской Федерации не
need Tatars" yes how will you live
нужно нам татар" да как вы будете жить
independently as long as you
самостоятельно как бы доколи ты это
know no Russian proverbs as long as you do
знаешь нет русские пословицы как бы
n't know no well then don't
доколи не знаешь нет вот вот тогда не
ask such questions
задавай такие вопросы
why well
почему
because damn explain it to you what should I explain to you well
ну потому что блин так объясни
you
что тебе объяснять ну вот ты мне тоже
explain it to me too damn that's how if that were to
объясни блин вот вот вот если бы вот вот
happen I don't
так вот случилось бы я же не
know how I know well come on
знаю я откуда знаю ну давай так
Tatarstan can survive without Moscow
татарстан без Москвы может выжить
that's how well for
это как
example there is no Moscow no no no
ну вот например Москвы нет не не нет
wait like there is no Moscow or like yes there is no Moscow there is no Moscow there is no
подожди как москвы нет или как да Москвы
Moscow let's say Trump inflicted
нет москвы Москвы нет скажем Трамп нанёс
nuclear strike on Moscow there is no Moscow yes that's it
ядерный удар по Москве москвы нет да всё
everyone started living without Moscow on their own
все стали жить без Москвы сами по себе
Tatarstan can survive in that case no of
татарстан может выжить в таком случае
course why well
нет конечно почему
because damn if they
ну потому что блин если в
come to Moscow and for us I
Москву придут же и за нами
mean who will come for you I don't know who is
в смысле кто за вами придёт не знаю кто
in Moscow who is in
в Москву кто в
Moscow you say there is no Moscow Trump
Москву ты же говоришь Москвы нету трамп
and who is who well well Trump will come then so
а кто кто ну вот вот Трамп придёт значит
why Trump you do
так а зачем Трампу вы
n't know why he Moscow is
не знаю а зачем он Моск
just by right of the
просто по праву
strong and by right of the strong he will
сильного и вот по праву сильного он и
come here I
придёт сюда же
mean it turns out you there uh can't
в смысле то получается вы там ээ не
imagine how you can
представляете как вы сможете
earn Tatarstan itself without this
зарабатывать Татарстан сам без этого
without Moscow so listen man I don't think about it
без Москвы так слушай мужик я насчёт
at all you
этого вообще не
know I live my
думаю понимаешь я вот живу вот своей
boring life at home work at home work I do
скучной жизнью дома работа дома работа я
n't think about it at all to be
вот насчёт этого вообще не думаю если
honest I understood in short it's hard what do you do
честно понял короче тяжело а кем ты
I work at a factory what do you do as a
я на заводе работаю
worker at a factory well as a fitter or a
на заводе рабочим
lumberjack
ну кем слесарем с лесарем
what kind of factory
что за завод
[ __ ] well and I don't know how to
бля ну а на завод я не знаю как как тебе
tell you what kind of factory if I
сказать в смысле что за завод если бы
told you what you produce there what you
сказал бы что выпускаете там чем
do I would tell you:
занимаете я бы тебе сказал бы:
"We produce tableware" what kind of tableware do you
"Выпускаем посуду" да что за посуду вы
produce
выпускаете
cast
литую
tableware aluminum cast tableware
посуду алюминиевая литая посуда
what do you think why Putin filled
как считаешь почему Путин наполнул
Ukraine
Украину
what Putin did why Putin attacked
что Путин сделал почему Путин напал на
attacked Ukraine I don't think that
путин напал на Украину я не считаю то
what Putin hello
что что Путин здравствуйте
hello I'm from Ukraine the city of
здравствуйте я из Украины город
Khmelnitsky where are you from
Хмельницкий вы откуда
I'm from Russia well and the city the city of
я откуда из России ну а город город
Moscow you have I see two flags there
Москва у вас я так смотрю два флага там
yes and which one is the bottom I don't know can you
да а какой нижний не знаю вы можете
show me I wonder I just can't
показать интересно просто я не могу
understand what kind of flag
понять что за флаг
yes yes and Turkey I got it all yeah and what are you by
да да а Турция всё понял угу а вы по
nationality
национальности кто
half Russian half Ossetian
а наполовину русский наполовину осетин
cool and what about the flag of Turkey I
прикольно а что флаг Турции
wonder and do you know the Finnish language no it's
интересно и финский язык знаете нет
just that my father is from Northern Setia from
просто у меня отец из Северной Сетии из
Ladikavkaz I'm
Ладикавказа
also half online but my mother is
я наполовину тоже сети но у меня мама
Ukrainian yeah well I don't know I got it how did it
укринг угу ну я нет не знаю понял а как
happen you grew up not
так получилось вы выросли вообще не в
online at all this is your father's side and why did
сети это отцовская линия а почему отец
n't your father talk to you
не разговаривал с вами
divorced I They are parents divorced I
разведены я Они родители разведены я не
have no well I have no desire to communicate with him in
имею ну не имею желания с ним общаться в
general yes but this is the blood of your people you
целом да но это кровь твоего народа ты
didn't want to teach
не хотел учить
and didn't want to teach
а не хотел учить
Ossetian language well I haven't gotten to
осетинский язык ну пока что не дошёл до
that yet there's still
этого
time do you at least know our
ещё время есть ты хоть знаешь наш
great poet Kostakhi Tagurov I honestly don't
великий поэт Костахи Тагуров я честно
know much about Ossetia in general
насчёт Осетии в целом мало чего знаю у
he has a very cool verse
него есть очень классный этот стих
called Vladikavkaz
называется Владикавказ
it's a poetic language very yeah yeah it sounds
это поэтический язык очень угу да звучит
really good but in
на самом деле хорошо а
general what language group does this
вообще какая языковая группа у этого
language belong to m language group what language does this
языка м языковая группа какая у этого
language belong to Iranian-Serman
языка иранносрманский
yeah yeah that is to say it can be similar to Persian
угу то есть с персидским он может похож
yeah well Iran is not Persian but Farsi it's
да быть ну ирань не персидский а фарси
called in Yes Farsi Irani Farsi
это называется в Да фарси ирани фарси
language is the same Iranian Ossetians are an
язык это тот же ирано осетины - это
Iranian-speaking people we yeah yeah it's interesting well I'll
ираноязычный народ мы да угу интересно
come to that somehow but it's
ну как-нибудь приду к этому а вот
interesting well uh very many words uh in the
интересно ну э очень многие слова ээ в
Russian language are borrowed from Farsi
русском языке заимствованы из фарси
borrowed from Ossetian and from
заимствованы из осетинских и из
Sarmatian different dialects uh-uh it's very
сарматских разных наречий вот э-э очень
interesting because we are Ossetians yes we
интересно потому что мы осетины да мы
see this similarity yeah you as a person it's
видим эту схожсть да ты как человек вот
interesting Ossetian but haven't heard the
интересно осетин но не слышал
Asistin language let me say some of those
асистинского языка давай те некоторые
words and you will
слова буду говорить а ты будешь
try to find an analogue in  in Russian yeah
попробовать найти аналог в русском
okay yeah machiko
о'кей да мачико
machiko stepmother no sword
мачико мачиха нет меч
mm sword the thing is that the sword was brought to the territory
мм меч дело в том что меч на территорию
where the Slavs lived from Asia from
где жили славяне да принесён из Азии из
just the Sarmatian tribes ours brought the
как раз сарматские племена наши принесли
sword and in ancient Slavic yeah it was also
меч и в древнеславянском да он тоже
called not a sword this name was already shortened that's
назывался не меч это уже укоротилось
because it was a weapon yeah
название вот потому что именно оружие да
it very often
оно очень часто
acquired a name from neighboring peoples
приобретало название из соседних народов
who were like for example the Turkic
которые были ког например вот тюркские
peoples brought the word shashka yeah well
народы принесли слово шашка да ну вот
such a saber sashka yeah okay yeah okay but
такую саблю сашка да о'кей да о'кей а
such a word haleb
вот такое слово халеб
bread can be yeah bread khalip khalip
хлеб может быть да хлеб халип халип -
is bread yeah about poshche also to the territory of this
это хлеб да о поще тоже на территорию
modern Russia yeah
вот это современной России да технологии
bread baking technologies came yeah from a more
выпекания хлеба пришли да из более
developed Asian civilization well you
развитой вот этой азиатской цивилиза ну
see very much in Indo-European languages ​​they are
видишь очень в индоевропейские языки они
very similar because
очень похожи потому что переплеталось
different cultures were intertwined and
культуры разные и такие там современные
some modern things there may be incomprehensible there may
какие-то вещи могут там непонятно может
diverge yeah but like or you will
расходиться да но вот ээ такие как или
also recognize this now milk milk
вот это тоже сейчас узнаешь молок
milk yeah yeah yeah such things
молоко молоко угу да вот такие ээ вещи
very-very similar or here in
очень-очень совпадают или вот на
Steninsky I will now count to
сетинском я сейчас тебе посчитаю до
ten for you yes atin kuto tyre chats poty shoty
десяти да атин куто тыре чаты поты шоты
city oty naty teny teny
сити оты наты
in the last teny it is like ten na like well
тени тени в последне тени оно как тен на
in many yes in many
как ну во многих да во многих
international languages ​​yes it is similar yes well
интерпейских языках да схоже да
if a person who speaks Steninsky
ну если человек владеющий астинским
ends up among the
окажется м среди
Kurdish population then it is better for him not to
населения курдов то ему лучше не не
say the word 10 natis well no well the Kurdish
говорить слово 10 натис ну не ну курский
language is a little different yes they will not
язык немножко другой да его его там не
understand it there yes yes they will understand it as an insult
поймут да да поймут как оскорбление
well it is interesting in fact well Turkish
ну интересно на самом деле ну турецкий
yes oh more precisely I apologize Steninsky yes
да ой точнее извиняюсь стинский да вот
in fact there are probably many borrowed
на самом деле много наверное позаимство
words but with Turkish it also seems to me let's say
слов но с турецким тоже мне кажется
checkers as you said yogurt
допустим шашки как вы сказали йогурт
also in theory the Turkish
тоже по идее турецкое
word also came from them and
слово тоже пришло от них и у нас вообще
in general in Russia we have many nationalities of
в целом в России много национальностей
peoples living
народов живёт
and among them there are many Turkic speaking Turkic speaking
и среди них есть много тюр тюркоязычных
yes yes and they are
тюкоязычных да да и вот у них прямо
very similar to each other yes
очень похожи между собой да
that is why in general in this regard I
поэтому меня вообще в этом плане ну я
have an advantage over others
имею преимущество перед другими потому
because knowing Turkish  I can
что зная турецкий язык я могу учить с
easily learn another Turkic language
лёгкостью другой тюркский язык потому
because the grammar is very similar to them, the
что грамматика очень похожа у них
main thing is the vocabulary, just learn it
главное словарный запас просто выучить
in the language you want to learn,
на том языке который ты хочешь выть
well, in our Ossetian language, the
выучить ну у нас в осетинском языке
grammar is very complex if you look,
очень сложная грамматика если посмотреть
well, for Russians, for Russians who
ну для россиян для русских которые
know, do you know Austin, yes, yes, well,
знаете А вы знаете Остинский да да да ну
as I know, I communicated, my father is Ossetian, he
как знаю я общался у меня отец Осетин он
communicated with me in Ossetian, I
со мной общался на Осетинском я писать
can write, yes, but I may not have the
могу да но я у меня возможно акцент не
same accent as the residents of Ossetia, because
такой как у жителей Осети потому что я
when I meet guys from Ossetia, I communicate with them
когда встречаю ребят из Осетии я с ними
in Ossetian, and I tell him:
на Осетинском общаюсь да и я ему говорю:
"Ethyl" and some of my consonants, they
"Этил" и некоторые мои созвучи они
ask again, so it is clear that I
переспрашивают так потому что видно я
still grew up in a Slavic-speaking environment,
всё-таки вырос в славяноязычной среде
and the only native speakers I
да и носителей языка у меня был
actually had were my father, and there, plus, in
фактически только отец а там плюс в
Ossetia itself, there are different dialects, and for
самой ээ Осетии есть разные наречия и у
example, my father, in fact, is not a
меня например отец по сути это же не
literary language, he spoke to me,
литературным языком он со мной
but in the dialect where he comes from,
разговаривал да а тем наречием откуда он
yes, he is a Degorian, and the Ironians,
родом да вот он дегорец у меня и иронцы
for example, no longer quite me
например уже меня не совсем не
they ask again
переспрашивают
yeah and can you please
угу а можете пожалуйста
say house in Austin and from house
сказать дом на Остинском и из дома
and you want to look at grammar yeah
а ты хочешь грамматику посмотреть да да
interesting like here house and look I'll
интересно как вот дом и смотри я тебе
tell you house from house and to house yeah
скажу дом из дома и в дом угу
kato and kato
като и като
akato and kato akato and kato izma akato to
акато и като акато и като изма акато в
house
дом
yeah that is
угу
at the beginning a
то есть это в начале
preposition is added
добавляется предлог
preposition kato and kato akato yeah interesting well
предлог като и като акато угу интересно
how does it turn out in Russian that is house
ну как в русском получается то есть дом
from house to house that is Yes yeah but Yes but in
из дома в дом то есть Да да но Да но на
writing our prepositions merge that is
письме у нас сливаются предлоги то есть
akato is written as one word and kato is also
акато пишется одним словом и като тоже
written as one word I understood it
пишется одним словом я понял
just a preposition is added at the beginning
просто в начало добавляется предлог
interesting
интересно
okay let's run all the best
хорошо давай побегу всего хорошенького
pleasant meet sit on
приятного встрети сиди на
Hello hello
Здравствуйте здравствуйте
and what are you talking about
а чём общаетесь
I understand you are currently on the YouTube channel
я как понял вы сейчас YouTube канале
yeah
проводите да
what do you want to talk about what's the
о чём хотите вы общаетесь у вас какой
moment you have there well I generally
там вот момент ну я вообще с россиянами
try to talk to Russians about the war because
стараюсь общаться о войне потому что у
we are currently at war between our
нас сейчас идёт война между нашими
countries so I'm interested in this topic
странами поэтому мне интересна эта тема
and what do you want to talk about well let's talk about
а вы о чём хотите ну давайте поговорим о
what you think about  let's what's the
том о чём вы думаете давайте какие
problem I'm from the city of Khmelnitsky
проблемы я из города Хмельницкий вы
where are
откуда
you from Dagestan
я из Дагестана
Avari Kumyk Lak Tabasran Dorgin
авариц кумык лакец табасранец доргинец
Dargin
даргинец
my father is Latik
у меня отец латиц
that's good so I'm asking the Russians how do
это хорошо вот я у россиян спрашиваю как
you feel about the fact that Russia attacked
вы относитесь к тому что Россия напала
Ukraine that's
на Украину
bad
плохо
and why did it attack
а почему она напала
well according to our information you should have
ну по по нашей информации вы должны были
attacked us so we attacked you
на нас напасть вот мы и напали на вас
cool or maybe it was worth waiting
прикольно а может стоило подождать
wait one day for us to start
подождать один день чтобы мы начали
attacking and then the whole world would see that
нападать и тогда весь мир бы увидел что
we are bad you have already attacked us further well
мы плохие вы на нас уже напали дальше
maybe but nothing can be changed
ну может быть но уже ничего не поменяешь
already happened
уже произошло
understood do you support Russia's actions in
понял вы поддерживаете действия России в
this
этом
I do not support any actions of
я вообще не продерживаю никакое действие
any country at all because because of this
никакой страны потому что из-за этого
people are dying
люди погибают
and who is to blame for this war
а кто виноват в этой войне
what do you think I think Putin Russia
как вы думаете я думаю что Путин Россия
Russians
россияне
and why do you think so now I
а почему вы так думаете я теперь у вас
asked you I
спросил я вас
asked you who is to blame you snapped at me
спросил кто виноват вы срезались на меня
I answered you now answer me
я вам ответил теперь ответьте вы
well your president
вот хорошо ваш президент
Zelensky who is he anyway
Зеленский он кто вообще сам по себе
when the war started what does
когда война началась причём тут
Zelensky have to do with it when the war started Zelensky  I
Зеленский когда война начала Зеленский
also played Pico on Real in
ещё пико на реале играл в четырнадцатом
2014 well there is no stop in
году ну он же там нет стоп в
2014 they started to step on the gas Crimea
четырнадцатом году газовать начали крым
Donetsk Lugansk was taken I am asking you
Донецк Луган забрали я же вас спрашиваю
why did you attack Ukraine who is to blame
зачем напали на Украину кто виноват
I answered this question we have rumors we have this
вот я же вам ответил на этот вопрос мы
information
по слухам у нас вот такая информация у
you don't know rumors you look at yourself
вас не знаете послухам ты по себя смотри
not as information you as a person
не как информация вот ты как человек
tell me I as a person think because
скажи я как человек думаю из-за того что
Ukraine had to pay Russia for
Украина должна была России заплатить за
gas
газ
this is my opinion so tell me that is you
это моё мнение так расскажи то есть вы
attacked us because Ukraine had to
напали на нас потому что Украина должна
pay for gas you didn't say we
была заплатить за газ ты не сказал мы
attacked you first of all this also
напали на вас в первую очередь это тоже
concerns
касается
where did you get this about gas this is an
а откуда ты это взял про газ это
interesting version come on well here's
интересная версия давай
how where do you look read the
ну вот как откуда посмотрите почитайте
information
информацию
where did you get this well my opinion this is
ну откуда ты взял это ну моё мнение это
purely my personal opinion and for what gas Ukraine didn't
чисто лично моё мнение а за какой газ не
pay
заплатила Украина
region gas regular natural gas
регион газ обычный природный
for what year Ukraine didn't pay for
ну за какой год Украина не заплатила ни
any at all absolutely
за какой вообще абсолютно
stuck it gave him a normal amount that's how it
заторчала она ему нормальную сумму вот и
all started this all started because of
началось вот это всё началось из-за
this
этого
and where can I read about this that
а где можно прочитать про это что
Ukraine owed an amount  for gas
Украина задолжала сумму за газ
how where well
как где
where are you where did you read this on the
ну где вы это где вы это почитали в
internet on the internet on the internet yes I
интернете в интернете в интернете да
understood it was on the news there was a conversation about this well this
понял было на в новостях было за это
was about 10 years ago and 10 years ago
ну это лет 10 назад было а 10 лет назад
I understood well yes just in the fourteenth year in
понял ну да как раз в четырнадцатом году
my opinion just most likely understood
по-моему как раз скорее всего понял
understood that is Ukraine did not give money for gas
понял то есть Украина не отдала за газ
Russia started to fight with Ukraine
деньги Россия начала воевать с Украиной
no this is first of all I told you
нет это в первую очередь я же сказал вам
before that this is also first of all
до этого что это тоже в первую очередь
listen tell me this you as a person
слушай расскажи мне вот такое ты как
living in Dagestan yes I know that
живущий в Дагестане да я знаю что
Dagestan is a very depressed region
Дагестан - это очень депрессивный регион
yeah yeah economically how does it happen
да угу экономически как так получается
that in Russia there is oil gas gold
что в России есть нефть газ золото
diamonds everything the whole periodic table and people
алмазы всё вся таблица Менделеева а люди
live so poorly
так живут
and who said that they live poorly
бедно а кто сказал что они живут бедно
how much is the salary in
сколько зарплата в
Dagestan on average 70 to 100 what is the
Дагестане в среднем 70 до 100 какой в
average up to 100
среднем до 100
now we google look yes an ordinary sales An
сейчас гуглим смотри да обычный торговый
ordinary sales representative goes to
Обычный торговый представитель ходит по
shops earns 70-100.000
магазинам зарабатывает 70-100.000
so this is not average so just here is the
так это не средней так просто вот
average in  Makhachkala average salary
средняя в Махачкала средняя зарплата
53,000 net 46 well well so this is poverty this is
53.000 на руки 46 ну ну так это бедность
no why
это это нет почему
poverty and what in Ukraine was not poverty
бедность а что в Украине не бедность
was also poverty yes yes but in Ukraine there is
была тоже бедность да да но в Украине
no gas gold diamonds oil question how is it
нет газа золота алмазов нефти вопрос как
that Russia means
же так получается что Россия значит
something assumed How is it that
что-то предполо Как так получается что
Russia having such wealth and lives so
Россия имея такие богатства а живёт так
poorly
бедно
I answered to It does not live poor who
я же ответил на Не живёт она бедным кто
lives poor well well come on so how does it
живёт бедным хорошо хорошо давай так как
happen look come on so wait
так получается смотри давай так подожди
no question question no question I'll clarify no
нет вопрос вопрос нет вопрос уточняю нет
stop don't interrupt me I'm the elder don't interrupt me
стоп не перебивай меня я старший не
don't interrupt look how
перебивай меня не перебивай смотри как
is it that Russia has oil gas
получается что Россия имеет нефть газ
gold diamonds and salaries are six to seven times
золото алмазы а зарплата в шесть-7мь раз
less than in Germany
меньше чем в Германии
I'll tell you one thing now buddy right
я тебе одно скажу сейчас дружище вот
now people are watching your stream and
сейчас твой стрим смотрят люди и тебе
commenting on you there and I'm one of our people
там комментируют а я вот из наших людей
there in the comments no one
там на в комментариях никто ничего не
can write anything that is it turns out
может написать то есть это получается
unfair we can't tell you
несправедливо мы не можем сказать вам
eve to your questions there in the stream
эветь на ваши вопросы там в стриме
that's right not in the stream here I'm
правильно так не в стриме вот я с тобой
talking to you you answer my questions you you
общаюсь ты отвечай на мои вопросы ты ты
now  streaming on YouTube you are now your
сейчас стримишься в Ютубе ты сейчас твои
same your same people with I stream on YouTube yes
же ваши же люди с Я стримлю в Ютубе да
but you tell me why you live poorly
но ты мне скажи почему ты бедно живёшь
if you have oil gas diamond there is poor
если у тебя нефть газ алмаз есть бедно
buddy I do not live poorly why do you
дружище я не живу бедно почего ты за
live poorly there is look you have
живу бедно есть у вас смотри у вас есть
oil gas diamond why poor let's
нефть газ алмаз почему бед давай
talk the same way you talked yes
разговариваем так же как ты разговал да
why Makhachkala I look here the salary is
почему махачкала я смотрите тут зарплата
53,000 yes it is 530 euros if in Germany the
53.000 да это 530 евро если в Германии
average salary is 5,000 euros 10 times
средняя зарплата 5.000 евро в 10 раз
more how is it Germany buys gas from
больше как это Германия покупать газ у
Russia and Russia is poor to live why can't I
Россия а Россия бедна жить почему не
understand me are you parodying in front of the
могу понять меня пародируешь перед
public you to I am not parodying you in front of the
публикой ты к Я не пародирую тебя перед
public I am asking you in a
публикой я тебя спрашиваю на понятном
language you understand come on tell
тебе языке давай скажи
me why you live so poorly if
мне почему ты так бедно живёшь если у
you have gas gold diamond and what did you
тебя есть газ золото алмаз а а чего ты
know that I lived poorly because you
знал что я бедно жил потому что ты бедно
live poorly I look at your this and say
живушь я посмотреть твой это и говорить
here it says that the average salary Makhachkala
тут пишет что средние зарплаты махачкала
53,402 rubles how is it  so if Russia
53.402 руб как это так если Россия
sells oil, gas, diamonds to Germany and
продавать в Германию нефть газ алмаз а
Germany lives richer if Germany pays
Германия жить богаче если Германия
Russia its money and Russia
платить России свои деньга а Россия
lives so poorly in
живёт так бедно в
oh-ho-ho that's how poor you live and what's
охо-хо-хо вот это ты бедно живёшь и
more yes you live in Putin's Izhiv
больше того да ты живёшь в ижишь Путина
why are you doing this dear
зачем ты такое делаешь дорогой
Yahvai if you remember who Imam
яхвай ты если помнишь кто такой был имам
Shamil was yes there is Imam Shamil and you against
Шамиль да вот есть имам Шамиль а ты на
his
его
background it's like
фоне это как и
Shamil Shamil is not the same there is such I'll
Шамиль шамиль не равно есть такой я тебе
tell you this no not everything listen further
вот что скажу нет не всё слушай дальше
listen further to me
слушай дальше меня
you are about your people who you are about your
ты по своего народа котора ты по свой
people yes you are sitting there in this and Yes you
народ да ты там сидишь в этот и Да ты
go home yes you have a donkey no you have a
иди к себе да есть у тебя Ишак нет у
wife no wife you have a donkey Russian
тебя жена нет жена есть Ишак русский
Vanka took your wife yes and you
Ванька забрал твой жена да а тебе
were left with a
остался
donkey because you are sitting there in Makhachkala
Ишак потому что ты там в Махачкала
you are like: "Look at who
сидишь ты такой: "Бе посмотри кого у
your house has a curtain behind it all
тебя дом сзади занавеска вообще такой
yeah" there is nothing like that at all behind there is
да" нет ничего такой вообще сзади там
this you yourself your hair has fallen out there are not even vitamins
этот сам ты волосы выпали даже витаминов
you could eat normally you would take some meat
нету ты кушал бы нормально какое-то мясо
lamb kebab there or what did you
бы взял шашлык баранина там или что
take subscribe to I do
взял підпишись на
n’t know why you are there for what else you are there to
й не знаю для чго це тобі для чого ще
marvel at the rest for you
тобі там дивитись на ост але для тебе це
one or two or three clicks and you support
оди два або три клика але ти підтримаєш
me and I will say: “Wow, I have
мене и я буду казати: "Уау в мене там
a lot of followers there and I will be cool
купа фуловерів і в мене буде класний
Nestb work new cool videos subscribe
настб робити нові круті видео підпишись
to my Instagram Popik Andrey
на мій Instagram Попик Андрей
so let me check for you
отак давай я тебя чекаю